Guide to the Alexander L. George Student Unrest Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alexander L. George student unrest collection
1968-1972
SC0803
George, Alexander L.
0.75 Linear feet (2 boxes)
This collection pertains to the antiwar movement of college students and the resulting disruptions on college campuses, in particular that of Stanford University. Included are press releases from the Stanford News Service, memoranda, statements and handouts from student organizations, statements by the Stanford administration, issues of the Campus Report, magazine articles, and clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2006 by Mrs. Alexander L. George.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Alexander L. George was professor of political science at Stanford University from 1968 until his retirement in 1990.
Description of the Collection
Collection pertains to the antiwar movement of college students and the resulting disruptions on college campuses, in particular that of Stanford University. Collection includes press releases from the Stanford News Service, memoranda, statements and handouts from student organizations, statements by the Stanford administration, issues of the Campus Report, magazine articles, and clippings. Incidents specific to Stanford include sit-ins at the Applied Electronics Laboratory, Encina Hall, and the Stanford University Hospital, and the dismissal of Prof. Bruce Franklin. Items of note include the booklet "The Goods on AEL declassified by the April 3rd Movement" (box 1, folder 1) and Yale University, 1968-69, Report of the President (box 2, folder 3).
Access Terms
Franklin, H. Bruce (Howard Bruce), 1934-; Student movements--California--Stanford.; Students--Political activity.
Collection Contents
- Stanford student unrest, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Stanford student unrest, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Stanford student unrest, clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Stanford student unrest, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Stanford student unrest, clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Stanford Ad Hoc Faculty Information Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Student unrest, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Outgoing letter, 1969 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Student unrest, clippings, 1968-69 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Student unrest, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- University of Wisconsin, Kaufman case, report, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)